Register of the T. V. (Tzu-wen) Soong papers
Hoover Institution Archives
T. V. (Tzu-wen) Soong papers
1920-1999
73004
Hoover Institution Archives
63 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 2 envelopes, 3 album boxes, 1 oversize folder, 2 microfilm reels, memorabilia (33.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, memoranda, reports, and photographs relating to political and economic conditions in China during the 1930s and 1940s; Chinese foreign relations, especially with the United States; events in China during World War II; and wartime Chinese diplomacy, especially regarding Sino-American relations. Also available on microfilm (80 reels). Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Soong, T. V. (Tzu-wen), 1894-1971
Access
Microfilm use only. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1973, with increments received in 2004 and 2006.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Also available on microfilm (80 reels). Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Biographical Note
1894 December 4 Born, Shanghai, China
1915 B.A., Harvard University
T.V. Soong also received two honorary doctorates, from Columbia University and Yale University.
1915-1917 Graduate studies, Columbia University, New York
1917-1923 Secretary, Han-yeh-p'ing iron and coal complex, China (Hanyang steel mill, Tayeh iron mines, P'inghsiang coal mines). Also involved in trade and banking circles, Shanghai
1923 Manager, Salt Administration in Kwangtung and Kwangsi provinces
1924 Manager, Central Bank, Canton Member, Committee for Food Control
1925 Minister of Finance, National Government, Canton
1926 Member, Central Executive Committee Minister of Commerce Member, National Government (State) Council
1927 Minister of Finance, Wuhan Government Member, Standing Committee, Government Council Member, Military Council Member, Kuomintang Political Council
1928 Minister of Finance, Nanking government Governor, Central Bank of China, Shanghai
1932-1933 Acting President, Executive Yuan, Nanking
1933 Head of Chinese Delegation to the World Economic Conference, London Resigned government posts, except for National Economic Council
1934 Founder, China Development Finance Corporation
1938 Acting Chairman, National Aeronautical Affairs Commission
1940-1942 Personal representative of Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek to President Franklin D. Roosevelt, Washington, D.C.
1942-1945 Minister of Foreign Affairs
1944 Acting President, Executive Yuan
1945 Head of Chinese Delegation, United Nations Conference, San Francisco Elected as one of four chairman of United Nations Conference
1945-1947 President, Executive Yuan
1947-1949 Governor, Kwangtung Province
1949-1950 President, Bank of China, Taiwan
1971 Died, San Francisco, California; interred, New York
Scope and Content of Collection
The Hoover Institution acquired fifty-eight boxes of T. V. Soong papers from the Soong family in the 1970s. Of this material, thirty-nine boxes have been available for research since their acquisition. The other nineteen boxes were closed by the family during the lifetime of Madame Chiang Kai-shek, who passed away on October 23, 2003. This finding aid describes the papers in those fifty-eight boxes (re-housed into fifty seven boxes for preservation in 2012).
In 2004 the family donated additional Soong papers, which are described below as Incremental Materials. On April 26, 2004, the nineteen boxes of papers closed by the family since the 1970s and all of the papers acquired in 2004 were opened for research.
The family could not authorize the release of security-classified government documents, which were present in both the original acquisition and the 2004 addition. The vast majority of these, including all classified documents in the original acquisition, were declassified by the U.S. government and opened in summer 2004. In January 2005, the declassified documents were returned to their original folders; a list of these folders follows this note.
While the arrangement of folders and papers remains unchanged since the 1970s, the fifty-eight boxes in the original acquisition were renumbered in April 2004 and revised in August 2012. Originally organized as Schedule A, boxes 1-40, and Schedule B, boxes 1-18, the schedules were eliminated and the boxes numbered sequentially from 1 to 57. A box conversion chart is available upon request.
As a standard archival preservation procedure, use copies have been substituted for original documents in some cases. All information contained in the original documents is open and available in the use copies. Upon request, the original documents may be viewed under direct supervision by archives staff.
Scope and Content Note for the Incremental Materials
Increments in the T. V. Soong collection were acquired in 2004 and 2006, when the Soong family descendents augmented the existing T. V. Soong collection at the Hoover Institution Archives.
These incremental materials describe such turning points as the abduction of Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek in 1936 (the Xi'an incident), the dismissal of General Joseph Stilwell, and the framing of the Sino-Soviet Treaty of 1945. A major component of the collection includes T. V. Soong's notes, memoranda, confidential telegrams, financial records, and correspondence with Chiang Kai-shek and other government officials in China's wartime government. It also includes personal correspondence exchanged between members of the Soong family, including T. A. Soong, Soong Ai-ling (Madame H. H. K'ung), Soong Ching-ling (Madame Sun Yat-sen) and Soong Mei-ling (Madame Chiang Kai-shek). Selected telegrams in the T. V. Soong papers were transcribed and translated from Chinese to English and published in a bilingual edition as Song Ziwen yu wai guo ren shi wang lai han dian gao = T. V. Soong: Important Wartime Correspondences (1940-1942), Hsiao-ting Lin and Wu Jingping, editors (Shanghai: Fudan University Press, 2009). This publication is available in the Hoover Archives reading room.
The arrangement of this material has been closely maintained as it was received from the donors in 2004 and 2006. In some cases, as a standard archival preservation procedure, use copies have been substituted for original documents. All information contained in the original documents is open and available in the use copies. Upon request, the original documents, which comprise the Restricted Material series, may be viewed under direct supervision by archives staff. This series includes all restricted originals from boxes 1 to 64.
The family could not authorize the release of security-classified government documents, which were present in both the original acquisition and the 2004 addition. The vast majority of these were declassified by the U.S. government and opened in summer 2004. In January 2005 the declassified documents were returned to their original folders. A list of folders containing declassified documents re-filed in January 2005 is available below.
List of Folders Containing Declassified Documents Refiled in January 2005
CORRESPONDENCE
Box 4, folders 14 and 23
Box 5, folder 2
Box 6, folder 38
Box 7, folders 1 and 10
Box 9, folder 27
Box 10, folder 14
OFFICE FILE
Box 12, folder 2
Box 16, folder 4
Box 18, folder 6
Box 19, folder 7
SUBJECT FILE
Box 20, folder 12
Box 21, folder 4
Box 22, folder 3
Box 24, folders 2 and 3
Box 26, folder 7
Box 27, folders 2, 4, 7 and 13
Box 28, folders 13 and 14
Box 29, folder 6, 8 and 14
Box 30, folder 3
Box 31, folders 1, 10 and 13
Box 34, folders 2 and 3
FORMERLY CLOSED MATERIAL
Boxes 36 to 39
INCREMENTAL MATERIALS
Box 61, folder 14
Box 62, folder 3
Box 62, folder 4
Box 62, folder 5
Box 62, folder 6
Box 62, folder 8
Box 62, folder 11
Box 62, folder 16
Box 62, folder 17
Box 62, folder 22
Box 63, folder 1
Box 63, folder 24
Box 63, folder 31
Box 64, folder 1
Box 64, folder 2
Box 64, folder 3
Box 64, folder 5
Box 64, folder 8
Box 64, folder 14
Box 64, folder 15
Box 64, folder 24
Chiang, Kai-shek, 1887-1975.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; China--Economic conditions--1912-1949.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China--Foreign relations.; China--History--Republic, 1912-1949.; China--Politics and government--1912-1949.; Reconstruction (1939-1951)--China.; Statesmen--China.; United States--Foreign relations--China.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.
- Microfilm Reel Content Guide
  Other Finding Aids note
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- Correspondence, 1933-1960
  Scope and Contents note
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - General, 1940-1948 (Reel 1)
    Box/Folder 1: 1
  - Unidentified, 1940-1947
    Box/Folder 1: 2
  - Adler, Sol, 1946
    Box/Folder 1: 3
  - Alsop, Joseph, 1940-1945
    Box/Folder 1: 4-5
  - Ameghino, Cesar, 1944
    Box/Folder 1: 6
  - Andrew, George Findlay, 1940-1941
    Box/Folder 1: 7
  - Arce, José, 1946
    Box/Folder 1: 8
  - Arnstein, D. G., 1941
    Box/Folder 1: 9
  - Atcheson, George, Jr., 1944
    Box/Folder 1: 10
  - Avramow, Alberto J., 1941-1942
    Box/Folder 1: 11
  - Baron, Richard, 1942
    Box/Folder 1: 12
  - Bayne, E. A., 1947
    Box/Folder 1: 13
  - Beers, Leroy A., 1941
    Box/Folder 1: 14
  - Bell, B. W., 1941
    Box/Folder 1: 15
  - Beneš, Edvard, 1943
    Box/Folder 1: 16
  - Bien, S. Z., 1941
    Box/Folder 1: 17
  - Blaine, James G., 1942
    Box/Folder 1: 18
  - Blakeslee, George H., 1941
    Box/Folder 1: 19
  - Blum, Carl, 1944
    Box/Folder 1: 20
  - Boatner, H. L., 1941
    Box/Folder 1: 21
  - Bodenstein, I., 1941
    Box/Folder 1: 22
  - Bond, William L., 1941-1946
    Box/Folder 1: 23
  - Boucher, Hiram A., 1947-1948
    Box/Folder 1: 24
  - Bramlett, Ted, 1941
    Box/Folder 1: 25
  - Brennan, James, 1947
    Box/Folder 1: 26
  - Broadwell, Billy, 1942
    Box/Folder 1: 27
  - Bruce, Edward, 1941
    Box/Folder 1: 28
  - Buchanan, Edwin A., 1947
    Box/Folder 1: 29
  - Buckley, Walter, Mrs., 1940
    Box/Folder 1: 30
  - Bullitt, William C., 1940-1941
    Box/Folder 1: 31
  - Burck, Alfred D., 1942
    Box/Folder 1: 32
  - Burke, Daniel, 1940
    Box/Folder 1: 33
  - Calvet de Magalhãis, José, 1948
    Box/Folder 1: 34
  - Carl Bernadotte, Prince of Sweden, 1946
    Box/Folder 1: 35
  - Carter, Edward C., 1943-1945
    Box/Folder 1: 36
  - Carton de Wiart, Adrian C., 1945
    Box/Folder 1: 37
  - Chang, F., 1943-1948
    Box/Folder 1: 38-39
  - Chang, Loy, 1945-1946
    Box/Folder 1: 40
  - Chang, Peng-chun, undated
    Box/Folder 1: 41
  - Chang, Yung Nian, 1948
    Box/Folder 1: 42
  - Chao, C. M., 1948
    Box/Folder 1: 43
  - Chen, C. P., General, 1946
    Box/Folder 1: 44
  - Chen, Chak, 1945
    Box/Folder 1: 45
  - Chen, Doa Tung, undated
    Box/Folder 1: 46
  - Chen, Fu Kuang, 1945
    Box/Folder 1: 47
  - Chen, Reignson C., 1941-1946
    - Telegrams
      - 1941
        - Incoming
          Box/Folder 2: 1-2
        - Outgoing
          Box/Folder 2: 3
        - Outgoing (Reel 2)
          Box/Folder 2: 4
      - 1942
        - Incoming
          Box/Folder 2: 5-6
        - Outgoing
          Box/Folder 2: 7-8
    - Letters, 1941-1946
      Box/Folder 2: 9
  - Chennault, Claire L., General, 1943-1944
    Box/Folder 2: 10
  - Chenzen, Sophia H., 1943
    Box/Folder 2: 11
  - Chiang (?), Mon-lin, 1933
    Box/Folder 2: 12
  - Chien, Chang Tsu, 1942
    Box/Folder 2: 13
  - China Defense Supplies, Inc., 1942-1944
    Box/Folder 3: 1-3
  - China Defense Supplies, Inc. (Reel 3)
    Box/Folder 3: 4
  - China Institute in America, 1942
    Box/Folder 3: 5
  - China
    - Ministry of Finance, 1942
      Box/Folder 3: 6
    - National Resources Commission, 1945
      Box/Folder 3: 7
  - China Purchasing Agency, 1946
    Box/Folder 3: 8
  - Chinese Government Information Office, 1947
    Box/Folder 3: 9
  - Chinese Legation - Bern, Switzerland, undated
    Box/Folder 3: 10
  - Chinese National Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (CNRRA), 1947-1948
    Box/Folder 3: 11
  - Chinese Naval Construction Mission, 1945
    Box/Folder 3: 12
  - Chinese Supply Commission, 1945-1946
    Box/Folder 3: 13
  - Ching, Tien Ku, 1943
    Box/Folder 3: 14
  - Chow, C. J., General, 1943-1944
    Box/Folder 3: 15
  - Chow, Felton, 1944
    Box/Folder 3: 16
  - Chow, W. K., 1946
    Box/Folder 3: 17
  - Chun, H. C., 1944-1945
    Box/Folder 3: 18
  - Chun, R. C., 1942
    Box/Folder 3: 19
  - Chung, Chee Yuan, 1948
    Box/Folder 3: 20
  - Chung, S. L., 1948
    Box/Folder 3: 21
  - Churchill, Winston, 1943
    Box/Folder 3: 22
  - Clark, Edwin N., 1946
    Box/Folder 3: 23
  - Clayton, William L., 1944-1945
    Box/Folder 3: 24
  - Cleveland, Harlan, 1947
    Box/Folder 3: 25
  - Copland, D. B., 1948
    Box/Folder 3: 26
  - Cousins, Garnett, 1942
    Box/Folder 3: 27
  - Davis, T. C., 1947-1948
    Box/Folder 3: 28
  - Eden, Anthony, 1943
    Box/Folder 3: 29
  - Elder, James C., 1940-1943
    Box/Folder 3: 30
  - Eu, Edward, 1943-1945
    Box/Folder 3: 31
  - Eu, Jenny, 1942
    Box/Folder 3: 32
  - Fang, C. H., General, 1946
    Box/Folder 3: 33
  - Foo, P. S., 1943
    Box/Folder 3: 34
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1942
    Box/Folder 3: 35
  - Friedman, I. S., 1945
    Box/Folder 3: 36
  - Gauss, Clarence, 1943
    Box/Folder 4: 1
  - Gawler, G. N., 1947-1948
    Box/Folder 4: 2
  - Gilpatric, Don, 1947-1948
    Box/Folder 4: 3
  - Grantham, Sir Alexander, 1948-1960
    Box/Folder 4: 4
  - Guillaume, R., 1949 (Reel 4)
    Box/Folder 4: 5
  - Halifax, Edward, 1st Earl of, 1942-1943
    Box/Folder 4: 6
  - Hall, R. O., 1948-1949
    Box/Folder 4: 7
  - Hall, Ronald, 1947-1948
    Box/Folder 4: 8
  - Han, Lih Wu, 1942-1943
    Box/Folder 4: 9
  - Harriman, W. Averell, 1950
    Box/Folder 4: 10
  - Henderson, Leon, 1945
    Box/Folder 4: 11
  - Hill, Creighton, 1941
    Box/Folder 4: 12
  - Ho, P. H., 1941-1947
    - Letters
      Box/Folder 4: 13-14
    - Telegrams
      Box/Folder 4: 15-18
  - Ho, Ying-ching
    Box/Folder 4: 19
  - Hollis, L. C., 1943
    Box/Folder 4: 20
  - Hong Kong & Whampoa Dock Co., Ltd., 1948
    Box/Folder 4: 21
  - Hongkong, Ronald, 1943
    Box/Folder 4: 22
  - Hoo, Victor, 1942-1944
    Box/Folder 4: 23
  - Hopkins, Harry, 1942-1945
    Box/Folder 4: 24
  - Hou, C. Y., 1946
    Box/Folder 4: 25
  - Howe, Clarence Decatur, 1949
    Box/Folder 4: 26
  - Hsi, Te-mou, 1941-1946
    Box/Folder 4: 27
  - Hsia, Pinfang, 1942-1943
    Box/Folder 4: 28
  - Hsieh, H. L., 1944-1945
    Box/Folder 4: 29
  - Hsu, Kwangtze W., 1940
    Box/Folder 4: 30
  - Hsu, Kwong-tse, 1945
    Box/Folder 4: 31
  - Hu, Lan Sung, 1948
    Box/Folder 4: 32
  - Hu, Shih, 1951
    Box/Folder 4: 33
  - Huang, H. J., 1943
    Box/Folder 4: 34
  - Huang, K. Loo, 1947
    Box/Folder 4: 35
  - Huo, Pao Tsai, 1945
    Box/Folder 4: 36
  - Hurley, Patrick J., General, 1945-1951
    Box/Folder 4: 37
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, American Council, 1940-1941
    Box/Folder 4: 38
  - Irving Trust Company, 1942
    Box/Folder 4: 39
  - Johnson, B. A., General, 1946
    Box/Folder 4: 40
  - Keswick, John, 1948
    Box/Folder 4: 41
  - Kiang, H. C., 1941-1945 (Reel 5)
    Box/Folder 5: 1
  - Kiang, P., General, 1944-1948
    Box/Folder 5: 2
  - King, Ernest P., Admiral, 1942
    Box/Folder 5: 3
  - King, P. Z., 1943
    Box/Folder 5: 4
  - King, Wunsz, 1943
    Box/Folder 5: 5
  - Koo, V. K. Wellington, 1941-1949
    - Telegrams, 1941-1948
      Box/Folder 5: 6-10
    - Letters, 1941-1949
      Box/Folder 5: 11
  - Koo, Y. C., 1934-1938
    Box/Folder 5: 12
  - Kuo, Ying Tsai, 1948 (Reel 6)
    Box/Folder 5: 13
  - Kwangtung Provincial Bank, 1948
    Box/Folder 5: 14
  - Kwei, C. T., 1943
    Box/Folder 5: 15
  - Kwok, Elsie, 1943
    Box/Folder 5: 16
  - Kwok, K. K., 1945
    Box/Folder 5: 17
  - Kwok, P. W., 1943
    Box/Folder 5: 18
  - Kwok, Shang Yu, 1948
    Box/Folder 5: 19
  - Laguardia, Fiorello, 1946
    Box/Folder 5: 20
  - Lawrence, Mr., undated
    Box/Folder 5: 21
  - Leahy, William D., Admiral, 1943
    Box/Folder 5: 22
  - Lee, Kan, Dr., 1942-1945
    Box/Folder 5: 23
  - Lee, T. C., Major, 1943-1945
    Box/Folder 6: 1
  - Lee, Tommy, 1942
    Box/Folder 6: 2
  - Lee, Wei-kuo, 1942-1945
    Box/Folder 6: 3
  - Li, K. C., 1942
    Box/Folder 6: 4
  - Li, Shu-fan, 1943-1946
    Box/Folder 6: 5
  - Li, Tu kung, 1942-1943
    Box/Folder 6: 6
  - Lieu, O. S., 1946
    Box/Folder 6: 7
  - Lim, Robert K. S., 1948
    Box/Folder 6: 8
  - Lin, D. Y., 1943
    Box/Folder 6: 9
  - Lin, W. Y., 1946-1948
    Box/Folder 6: 10
  - Ling, F. P., 1945-1946
    Box/Folder 6: 11
  - Little, Lester K., 1942-1948
    Box/Folder 6: 12
  - Liu, C. S., 1943-1946
    Box/Folder 6: 13
  - Liu, Chieh, 1945-1949
    Box/Folder 6: 14
  - Liu, Frank, 1944
    Box/Folder 6: 15
  - Liu, J. Heng, 1943-1944
    Box/Folder 6: 16
  - Liu, Ju-sung, 1948
    Box/Folder 6: 17
  - Look, Mang Hey, 1942
    Box/Folder 6: 18
  - Look, Vun Hou, 1942
    Box/Folder 6: 19
  - Lu, David, 1944
    Box/Folder 6: 20
  - Luce, Henry R., 1943-1949
    Box/Folder 6: 21
  - Ludden, Raymond P., 1948
    Box/Folder 6: 22
  - Lynott, George H., 1940-1941
    Box/Folder 6: 23
  - Ma, Te-chi, undated
    Box/Folder 6: 24
  - MacArthur, Douglas, General, 1948
    Box/Folder 6: 25
  - MacDonald, Malcolm, 1948-1953
    Box/Folder 6: 26
  - McHugh, J. M., 1942-1944
    Box/Folder 6: 27
  - Mackenzie King, W. L., 1943-1949
    Box/Folder 6: 28
  - McNeary H. G., 1940-1941
    Box/Folder 6: 29
  - Magruder, Carter B. (?), General, 1941-1942
    Box/Folder 6: 30
  - Mar, Pellican T., Admiral, 1946
    Box/Folder 6: 31
  - Martins, Maria, 1943-1945
    Box/Folder 6: 32
  - Maux, H. C., 1944
    Box/Folder 6: 33
  - Meyrier, Ambassador, 1948
    Box/Folder 6: 34
  - Mon, Yin Chung, 1943
    Box/Folder 6: 35
  - Morgenthau, Henry, Jr., 1941-1944
    Box/Folder 6: 36
  - Moore, Maurice T., Mrs., undated
    Box/Folder 6: 37
  - Mountbatten, Louis, 1943-1945
    Box/Folder 6: 38
  - Mowrer, Edgar, 1941-1945
    Box/Folder 6: 39
  - Murphy, Robert, 1956
    Box/Folder 6: 40
  - Murray, J. L., 1948
    Box/Folder 6: 41
  - Nelson, Donald M., 1944-1945
    Box/Folder 6: 42
  - Neprud, Carl, 1945
    Box/Folder 6: 43
  - Nicholson, Mr. (?), 1940
    Box/Folder 6: 44
  - Nixon, F. A., 1947
    Box/Folder 6: 45
  - Odlum, Victor W., General, 1948
    Box/Folder 6: 46
  - Olmstead, Ralph, 1946-1948
    Box/Folder 6: 47
  - Ovesen (?), Henrik, 1944
    Box/Folder 6: 48
  - Pan, S. H., 1946
    Box/Folder 6: 49
  - Paul-Boncour, Joseph, 1942-1943
    Box/Folder 6: 50
  - Peers, Roy G., 1945-1949 (Reel 7)
    Box/Folder 7: 1
  - Pei, Sung-Sen, 1942
    Box/Folder 7: 2
  - Pott, F. L. Hawks, 1947
    Box/Folder 7: 3
  - Prescott, William, 1952
    Box/Folder 7: 4
  - Price, E. G., 1948
    Box/Folder 7: 5
  - Price, Frank W., 1943
    Box/Folder 7: 6
  - Price, Harry, 1942-1944
    Box/Folder 7: 7
  - Quo, Tai-chi, 1942
    Box/Folder 7: 8
  - Rajchman, Ludwig, 1940-1945
    Box/Folder 7: 9
  - Remer, Carl, undated
    Box/Folder 7: 10
  - Rogers, Cyril, 1940-1946
    Box/Folder 7: 11-14
  - Rondon, L. & W Company (Hong Kong), 1940-1949
    Box/Folder 7: 15
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1942-1943
    Box/Folder 7: 16
  - Rorschach, A. L., 1947-1948
    Box/Folder 7: 17
  - Rouse, Rolla, 1948
    Box/Folder 7: 18
  - Royere, Pierre, 1948
    Box/Folder 7: 19
  - Samson, Henry R., 1947-1948
    Box/Folder 7: 20-21
  - Saturday Evening Post, undated
    Box/Folder 8: 1
  - Schubart, William H., 1942
    Box/Folder 8: 2
  - See Kung, Mr., 1946
    Box/Folder 8: 3
  - Seymour, Horace, 1943-1944
    Box/Folder 8: 4
  - Shaughnessy, Quinn, 1942
    Box/Folder 8: 5-6
  - Shen, H. J., 1946 (Reel 8)
    Box/Folder 8: 7
  - Shen, Shi-hwa, 1943-1944
    Box/Folder 8: 8
  - Shen, Yuen-ting, 1947
    Box/Folder 8: 9
  - Shih, Mr., 1946
    Box/Folder 8: 10
  - Shihsi, Hsu, 1945
    Box/Folder 8: 11
  - Smith, E. Groff, 1943
    Box/Folder 8: 12
  - Snow, Edgar, 1940-1941
    Box/Folder 8: 13
  - Spellman, Archbishop Francis J., 1943
    Box/Folder 8: 14
  - Steelzner, E., 1948
    Box/Folder 8: 15
  - Stein, Freiherr von, 1942
    Box/Folder 8: 16
  - Stein, Gunther, 1943
    Box/Folder 8: 17
  - Stettinius, Edward R., Jr., 1945-1946
    Box/Folder 8: 18
  - Stevenson, Ralph, 1947-1948
    Box/Folder 8: 19
  - Stuart, J. Leighton, 1947-1948
    Box/Folder 8: 20
  - Sun, Fo, 1942-1943
    Box/Folder 8: 21
  - Sun, Li-jen, 1947-1948
    Box/Folder 8: 22
  - Swing, Raymond, 1945
    Box/Folder 8: 23
  - Sze, Alfred, 1943-1945
    Box/Folder 8: 24-25
  - Sze, Deson, 1944
    Box/Folder 8: 26
  - Sze, Seeming, 1943-1945
    Box/Folder 8: 27
  - Tan, W. H., 1944-1948
    Box/Folder 8: 28
  - Tang, M. Y., 1942
    Box/Folder 8: 29
  - Tao, Zung-tse, 1945
    Box/Folder 8: 30
  - Tcheng, Pao King, 1942
    Box/Folder 9: 1
  - Thurber, H. R., 1948
    Box/Folder 9: 2
  - Ting, K. T., 1947
    Box/Folder 9: 3
  - Tong, Hollington, 1944-1945
    Box/Folder 9: 4
  - Trone, S., undated
    Box/Folder 9: 5
  - Townsend, Peter, 1947
    Box/Folder 9: 6
  - Tsai, S. M., 1942
    Box/Folder 9: 7
  - Tsai, T. W., 1945
    Box/Folder 9: 8
  - Tseng, T. K., 1943
    Box/Folder 9: 9
  - Tweedy, G., 1942-1944
    Box/Folder 9: 10-11
  - Tyrell, G. F., 1948
    Box/Folder 9: 12
  - U Sze Wing, 1946
    Box/Folder 9: 13
  - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA), 1947
    Box/Folder 9: 14
  - United States, China Relief Mission, 1947-1948 (Reel 9)
    Box/Folder 9: 15
  - United States, State Department, Historical Division, 1956
    Box/Folder 9: 16
  - Wallace, Henry, 1945
    Box/Folder 9: 17
  - Wang, C. C., 1946
    Box/Folder 9: 18
  - Wang, Shih-chieh, 1946-1948
    Box/Folder 9: 19-20
  - Wedemeyer, Albert C., General, 1944-1946
    Box/Folder 9: 21
  - Wei, Tao-ming, 1945-1946
    Box/Folder 9: 22
  - Wen, Y. C., 1941
    Box/Folder 9: 23
  - White, Harry, 1944-1945
    Box/Folder 9: 24
  - White, Theodore H., 1943-1948
    Box/Folder 9: 25
  - Whitney, Betsey C., 1952
    Box/Folder 9: 26
  - Willauer, Whiting, 1945
    Box/Folder 9: 27
  - Wilson Company, H. W., 1941
    Box/Folder 9: 28
  - Wong, K. H., 1945
    Box/Folder 9: 29
  - Wong, Wen-hao, 1945
    Box/Folder 9: 30
  - Woo, L. S., 1948
    Box/Folder 9: 31
  - Woo, Y. C., 1940-1941
    Box/Folder 9: 32
  - Wu, C. H., 1940
    Box/Folder 9: 33
  - Wu, K. C., 1943-1947
    Box/Folder 9: 34
  - Yang, S. Z., 1944-1945
    Box/Folder 9: 35
  - Yarnell, Harry E., Admiral, undated
    Box/Folder 10: 1
  - Yen, Y. C. James, 1943-1945
    Box/Folder 10: 2
  - Yin, Ernest R., 1945
    Box/Folder 10: 3
  - Yin, K. Y., 1945-1947
    Box/Folder 10: 4
  - Young, Arthur N., 1941-1945
    Box/Folder 10: 5
  - Youngman, William S., 1943-1948
    Box/Folder 10: 6-8
  - Yu, David, General, 1945
    Box/Folder 10: 9
  - Yui, O. K., 1942-1947
    Box/Folder 10: 10
  - Zi, Oliver, 1948
    Box/Folder 10: 11
- Office File, 1942-1949
  Telegrams sent and received while T. V. Soong held positions as Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek's personal representative to President Franklin D. Roosevelt, as Minister of Foreign Affairs, as Acting President of the Executive Yuan, and as Governor of Kwangtung Province. The telegrams are arranged chronologically. Security-classified telegrams have been declassified and are available in Formerly Closed Material.
  - Telegrams
    - Chungking - Washington, D.C., 1942 June 2-October 5 (Reel 10)
      Box/Folder 10: 12-14